CURRICULUM VITAE OF BUSISIWE MANDISA MAGAE

South African | African Leadership College, Powder Mill road, Pamplemousses, 21001 | +230 54722934 b.magae@alustudent.com

SUMMARY

High spirited individual who is passionate about tackling challenges and formulating solutions who gained soft skills required to work with different kinds of personalities and environments. Residential Advisor experienced in student leadership, guidance and support initiatives focused on making a difference in the community. Implemented service programs for student support and performance objectives to provide a safe and secure environment. Designed and implemented a nurturing and holistic environment with Residential life team.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Glasgow Caledonian University-Glasgow, Scotland

September 2021 - Current

Bachelor of Science - Computing

Fundamentals of Software Engineering, Network Technology, Programming, Mathematics, Database Development, Security Landscapes, Web Platform Development

African Leadership College – Pamplemousses, Mauritius

January, 2021 – September 2021

Leadership - Leadership Core

Relevant Coursework: Data and Decisions, Entrepreneurial Leadership, Communication for Impact, Global Challenges, Projects

Tshwane University of Technology – Pretoria, South Africa

January, 2019 – December, 2019

Higher Certificate in Industrial Engineering

Relevant Coursework: Industrial Engineering Practice, Engineering Work Systems, Technical Mathematics, Engineering Physics, Quality Systems and Process Improvements, Computer Literacy, Communication Skills

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Residential Advisor

September 2021 - Current

African Leadership College– Pamplemousses, Mauritius

- Maintained communication with students' counselors, instructors, and staff members to promote a supportive environment.
- Established consistent relationships with students to maintain professional boundaries.
- Organized and facilitated leadership programs created for residential students and leaders to cater for their leadership growth
- Assisted students in handling conflict to resolve problems.
- Organized events, promoted them and reported the outcomes and impact.
- Led hype and buzz team and used social media to bring awareness, including drafting emails.
- Enforced policies and safety standards through building and room rounds.
- Provided swift and knowledgeable emergency support in line with campus crisis protocols.
- Strategize to improve resident care and satisfaction and held weekly meetings with managers to advocate for resident needs.

Academic Officer

November 2019 - November 2020

Tshwane University of Technology, Polonaise residence - Pretoria , South Africa

- Maintained student database and electronic records for each student contact.
- Organize activities that best suit student needs and are most effective for their academics.
- Constantly check the progress of the system and student improvements in areas of focus.
- Answered student inquiries and resolved problems related to curriculum and course prerequisites.
- Provided support and guidance to students experiencing academic and personal troubles.
- Conducted seminars, workshops, and educational presentations for enrichment opportunities for students.
- Discussed and implemented student academic success strategies and development of study skills with mentors.
- Helped students with initial adjustment to university academic life and interpreted institutions policies and requirements.
- Worked with committee members to set residence policies and activities that would best benefit the students.

CURRICULUM VITAE OF BUSISIWE MANDISA MAGAE

Departmental Representative Chairperson

February 2019 - November 2019

Tshwane University of Technology, Faculty of Engineering- Pretoria, South Africa

- Head of Class Representatives in Industrial engineering
- Respond to student requests and needs
- Identified issues, analyzed information and provided solutions to problems faced by students.
- Quickly learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks, improving efficiency and productivity.
- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions that cater for both the department and students.

and

- Developed and maintained courteous and effective working relationships between students, myself and the department
- Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help wherever needed.
- Participated in team-building activities, leadership seminars and bootcamps to enhance working relationships

SKILLS

- Critical Thinking
- Staff Meeting Coordination
- Emergency/Crisis Response(Covid-19, Natural disasters, Medical)
- Student Needs Assessment
- Resident Supervision
- Activities Oversight
- Policy Enforcement
- Reporting Documentation
- Information and Data Management
- Active Listening
- Activities Oversight
- Team Supervision
- Leadership development
- Social media management

LANGUAGES

- Setswana– Native
 E
- English Proficient
- French- Beginner
- Zulu– Conversational